A Guide to the Margaret Freeman Cabell Papers 1910-1982
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- Series IV--Organizational Correspondence, n.d. 1926-1977
  - McBride (Robert M.) and Company 1931-1964 (Box 26)
  - McBride (Robert M.) and Company 1954-1961 (Box 26)
  - Miami Public Library 1952 (Box 26)
  - Modern Library 1952 (Box 26)
  - Mondadori (Arnoldo) Editore 1949 (Box 26)
  - Museum of the Confederacy 1971 (Box 26)
  - Musicians Club 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Nation 1928-1953 (Box 26)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People 1935 (Box 26)
  - National Genealogical Society 1955 (Box 26)
  - National League of American Pen Women 1928-1942 (Box 26)
  - National Society of the Colonial Dames of America 1963-1973 (Box 26)
  - National Theatre Service 1951 (Box 26)
  - New American Library of World Literature, Inc. 1957-1965 (Box 26)
  - New Republic 1930-1932 (Box 26)
  - New York American 1935 (Box 26)
  - New Yorker 1961 (Box 26)
  - New York Herald Tribune(Inita Van Doren) 1933-1955 (Box 26)
  - New York Herald Tribune(Lewis Gannett) 1956 (Box 26)
  - New York Herald Tribune(Lewis Samuels) 1932-1933 (Box 26)
  - New York Post(Sterling North) 1943 (Box 26)
  - New York Public Library 1956-1971 (Box 26)
  - New York World-Telegram(Sterling North) 1932-1949 (Box 26)
  - Northwestern University Radio Guild 1946-1947 (Box 26)
  - O. Henry Memorial Committee 1926 (Box 26)
  - Ober (Harold) Associates 1959 (Box 26)
  - Odyssey Press 1970 (Box 26)
  - Oglethorpe University Press 1932-1934 (Box 26)
  - Order of Bookfellows 1931 (Box 26)
  - Peabody Institute Library, n.d. (Box 26)
  - P.E.N. 1955-1973 (Box 26)
  - Penguin Books, n.d. 1946 (Box 26)
  - Peoples Library 1956 (Box 26)
  - Players Club 1926 (Box 26)
  - Plimpton Press 1927-1929 (Box 26)
  - Pocket Books, Inc. 1956 (Box 26)
  - Poe Foundation, Inc., n.d. 1964-1972 (Box 27)
  - Poetry 1952 (Box 27)
  - Poetry Society of Virginia (Harry M. Meacham) 1934-1971 (Box 27)
  - Enoch Pratt Free Library 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Princeton University 1963 (Box 27)
  - Prins and Prins 1967-1974 (Box 27)
  - Publishers' Weekly 1934 (Box 27)
  - Random House, Inc. 1932-1956 (Box 27)
  - Recording for the Blind, Inc. 1954-1956 (Box 27)
  - Republican National Committee 1940 (Box 27)
  - Reynal and Hitchcock, Inc. 1936 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Academy of Arts 1932 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Area Democratic Woman's Club 1971-1972 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Artists Association 1962 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Ballet 1972 (Box 27)
  - Richmond (City of) Department of Finance 1959-1965 (Box 27)
  - Richmond (City of) Department of Public Works 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Mercury 1972 (Box 27)
  - Richmond News Leader(Douglas S. Freeman, Louis R. Rubin, Jr.) 1931-1956 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Public Library 1957-1971 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Symphony 1971-1974 (Box 27)
  - Richmond Times-Dispatch(Virginius Dabney) 1939-1946 (Box 27)
  - Rinehart and Company 1946-1959 (Box 27)
  - Rockbridge Alum Springs Biological Laboratory 1945-1958 (Box 27)
  - Rockbridge Historical Society 1957 (Box 27)
  - Rusconi Editore 1972 (Box 27)
  - Sagamore Press, Inc. 1956 (Box 27)
  - St. Augustine Historical Society 1943 (Box 27)
  - St. Augustine Public Library 1944 (Box 27)
  - St. Augustine Record 1943 (Box 27)
  - St. Catherine's School 1954-1973 (Box 27)
  - St. James's Episcopal Church 1955-1983 (Box 27)
  - St. Martin's Press, Inc. 1972-1973 (Box 28)
  - Saturday Review 1967 (Box 28)
  - Saturday Review of Literature(William Rose Benet) 1929-1949 (Box 28)
  - Scott, Foresman and Company 1958 (Box 28)
  - Scribner Book Store 1953-1954 (Box 28)
  - Scribner's (Charles) Sons 1964-1970 (Box 28)
  - Seven Gables Book Shop (JBC Library) 1962-1975 (Box 28)
  - Shaw Society of America 1957 (Box 28)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc. 1930-1967 (Box 28)
  - Sixteenth Street Baptist Church 1963 (Box 28)
  - Society of Architectural Historians 1962 (Box 28)
  - Society of Colonial Wars in the State of Virginia 1971-1974 (Box 28)
  - Society of the Cincinnati 1937-1969 (Box 28)
  - Sons of Confederate Veterans 1973-1977 (Box 28)
  - Southern Heritage Foundation 1966 (Box 28)
  - Southern Literary Messenger 1942 (Box 28)
  - Southern Pacific Company Squires Book Dealer, n.d. (Box 28)
  - State Planters Bank of Commerce and Trusts 1961 (Box 28)
  - State Teachers College (Radford) 1933 (Box 28)
  - Steck Company Publishers 1950 (Box 28)
  - Stellar 1956 (Box 28)
  - Stokes (Frederick A.) Company 1934 (Box 28)
  - Strand Book Store, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Sun(NY) 1919 (Box 28)
  - Sunday Times(Johannesburg) 1931 (Box 28)
  - Suhrkamp Verlag 1971 (Box 28)
  - Thalhimers 1955-1965 (Box 28)
  - Tidewater Trail 1943 (Box 28)
  - Times Herald 1939 (Box 28)
  - Twayne Publishers, Inc. (Indiana University) 1966 (Box 28)
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy 1953 (Box 28)
  - University Center in Virginia, Inc. 1969 (Box 28)
  - University Microfilms, Inc. 1965-1967 (Box 28)
  - University of California 1957 (Box 28)
  - University of Chicago Quarterly Review 1946 (Box 28)
  - University of Florida 1932-1953 (Box 28)
  - University of Florida Press 1952-1960 (Box 28)
  - University of Iowa 1932 (Box 28)
  - University of Oklahoma Press 1962-1970 (Box 28)
  - University of Pennsylvania 1958-1965 (Box 28)
  - University of Pennsylvania Press 1962 (Box 29)
  - University of Richmond 1936-1968 (Box 29)
  - University of Richmond: Institute of Mediterranean Studies 1970-1971 (Box 29)
  - University of Richmond: Institute of Mediterranean Studies 1971-1974 (Box 29)
  - University of Richmond: Institute of Mediterranean Studies--Correspondence 1966-1972 (Box 29)
  - University of Richmond: Institute of Mediterranean Studies--Reports, Minutes 1966-1972 (Box 29)
  - University of Texas, n.d. 1931-1971 (Box 29)
  - University of Texas (F.W. Roberts) 1961-1965 (Box 29)
  - University of Virginia 1937-1964 (Box 29)
  - University of Virginia Alderman Library 1957-1971, 1979 (Box 29)
  - University of Virginia Bibliographical Socity (Matthew Bruccoli, Frances Brewer) 1956-1957 (Box 30)
  - University of Washington Chapbooks 1928 (Box 30)
  - University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee 1974 (Box 30)
  - Valentine Museum, n.d. 1956-1967 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Association of Teachers of English, n.d. (Box 30)
  - Virginia Cavalcade 1954 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (Richmond Professional Institute) 1968-1972 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library 1968-1976 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates, n.d. 1968 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates 1971-1978 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates 1969-1974 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates 1969-1970 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates 1970-1971 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates 1972 (Box 30)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Cabell Room 1972-1975 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Cabell Room Wood Samples, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Directory 1974 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Exhibit Cases 1971 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Exhibit of Virginia Writers 1971 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Goodman Library List, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Greek Party 1971 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Cabell Library Associates: Greek Sculpture 1970-1972 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Genealogical Society 1965-1974 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Historical Society (John M. Jennings) 1957-1971 (Box 31)
  - Virginia Museum 1971 (Box 32)
  - Virginia Press Women 1964 (Box 32)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review(F. Stringfellow Barr) 1926-1935 (Box 32)
  - Virginia State Library 1971 (Box 32)
  - Virginia Women's Forum 1966 (Box 32)
  - Virginia Writers Club 1966-1973 (Box 32)
  - Voyager 1955 (Box 32)
  - Warner Brothers 1935 (Box 32)
  - White (James T.) And Company, Publishers 1963 (Box 32)
  - Whittet and Shepperson 1970-1974 (Box 32)
  - Whittet and Shepperson 1970-1974 (Box 32)
  - Who's Who in the South and Southwest 1958 (Box 32)
  - Woman's Club 1955-1971 (Box 32)
  - World Mobility and Peerage 1963 (Box 32)
  - Xerox Company: University Microfilms 1967-1968 (Box 32)
  - Yale University 1948-1971 (Box 32)
- Series V--World War I Correspondence (MWF), n.d. 1917-1927
  - Anduin, William (Andy) 1919 (Box 32)
  - Compton, Earl 1919 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. 1918 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. 1917-1920 (Box 32)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1919-1923 (Box 32)
  - Photographs 1919 (Box 33)
  - Pellegrino, Maurizio 1920 (Box 33)
  - Reviewer, n.d. 1927 (Box 33)
  - Steck, Fred 1919 (Box 33)
  - Werschin, W.H. 1919 (Box 33)
- Series VI--Plays and Creative Writings
  - Blind 1932 (Box 33)
  - Social Security, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Things Not Seen, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Things Not Seen, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Who's Who in America, n.d. (Box 33)
  - These Mary, n.d. (Box 33-A)
  - Social Security, n.d. (Box 33-A)
  - Who's Who in America, n.d. (Box 33-A)
  - Poems and Creative Writing, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous) 1920-1933 (Box 34)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 34)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 34)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 34)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 35)
  - Plays (Notes?), n.d. (Box 35)
- Series VII--Margaret Waller Freeman Cabell Correspondence, n.d. 1931-1980
  - Branch, Effie, n.d. 1931 (Box 35)
  - Freeman, Charles 1948-1949 (Box 36)
  - Freeman, John Middleton 1947-1950 (Box 36)
  - Lectures 1933-1934 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous, n.d. 1952 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Architectural Notes, n.d. 1935-1938 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1918-1924 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, n.d. 1947-1949 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, n.d. 1934-1952 (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, Programs, etc. 1936-1940 (Box 37)
  - Rawling, Marjorie Kinnan 1948-1950 (Box 37)
  - Reviewer related correspondence, n.d. 1921-1923 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Randolph Ellet Alumnae Association, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Subseries--Client Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951
    - Clients A 1949 (Box 37)
    - Clients B 1949 (Box 37)
    - Clients C 1949-1950 (Box 37)
    - Clients D 1949-1951 (Box 37)
    - Clients H 1949-1950 (Box 37)
    - Clients L 1949-1951 (Box 37)
    - Clients M, n.d. 1948-1951 (Box 37)
    - Clients R 1948-1949 (Box 37)
    - Clients S 1949-1950 (Box 37)
    - Clients T 1949 (Box 37)
    - Clients V 1947-1950 (Box 38)
    - Clients Miscellaneous 1949 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 38)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 39)
    - Clients Correspondence, n.d. 1938-1951 (Box 39)
  - Subseries--Confederate Chapel Correspondence 1960-1973
    - Confederate Chapel Restoration 1960-1962 (Box 40)
    - Confederate Chapel Miscellaneous 1965-1973 (Box 40)
- Series VIII--John Brightwell Freeman Papers, n.d. 1930-1968
  - Business Records 1956-1965 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence 1965-1968 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence (Family), n.d. 1959-1967 (Box 40)
  - Correspondence (Time) 1957-1966 (Box 40)
  - Delta Psi (University Virginia Chapter) 1966 (Box 40)
  - Employment-W.M. Canby and Company, n.d. 1935 (Box 40)
  - Employment--DuPont, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Employment--Tampa, Florida, n.d. (Box 41)
  - Employment--War Assets/Price Administrative/Public Works 1947-1953 (Box 41)
  - Harris Gas Generating System 1930-1931 (Box 41)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency, n.d. (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous 1961 (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous Freeman Family Correspondence, Clippings, and Family Papers, n.d. 1950s-1970s (Box 41)
  - Resume and Applications, n.d. 1939 (Box 41)
  - St. Anthony Club 1954 (Box 41)
  - Taxes n.d. 1956 (Box 41)
  - University of Virginia 1966-1967 (Box 41)
- Series IX--John Middleton Freeman Papers, n.d.
  - Unknown, n.d., 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Charlottesville (Box 42)
  - Correspondence (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Atkins, Dan (attorney Malcom case) (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Buxton, Dimmock (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Cannariato, Joe (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Clark, Eliot (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Freeman, Lucy (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Freeman, Mary M. (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Graham, Ruth Bell (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Millham, Kay (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Peaslie, Kay (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Perry, Elmer (Box 42)
  - Correspondence--Steele, Dug (Box 42)
  - Khaki and her Friends (Box 42)
  - Mapmaker of Mott Street (Box 42)
  - Trial Data (Box 42)
  - Uncle Bruce and Irma (Box 42)
  - Veterans Hospital Commitment (Box 42)
  - Women (Box 42)
  - Women--Dogan, Susan (Box 42)
  - Women--Koch, Donna (Box 42)
  - Women--Malcom, Jennifer (Box 42)
  - Women--Vonherbulis, Kathy (Box 42)
  - After the Bath 1954 (Box 43)
  - Irene 1952 (Box 43)
  - Jamie Beverly at University Diner 1979 (Box 43)
  - Beautiful Joann, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Beatrice and Caroline, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jefferson at the Mineshaft 1979 (Box 43)
  - Denise at the Mineshaft 1979 (Box 43)
  - Cathy at the Rainbow, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Sketches of Unidentified People and Places (Box 43)
  - Diane Dixon, n.d. (Box 43)
  - John, You're not barred from the Mineshaft are you? (Box 43)
  - Unidentified Richmond House (Box 43)
  - B.R. Guest Drawing (Box 43)
  - Terrie's Mother's Photographs (Box 43)
  - Darleen at the Mineshaft, New Year's Eve 1979 (Box 43)
  - Sketches of a Young Girl at N.Y. Penn Station, and a former UVA Professor 1980 (Box 43)
  - Get that Goddam Grin off Your Face, Shithead!! You Hear?? (Box 43)
  - The Mapmaker of Mott Street (Box 43)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1979 (Box 43)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 43)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1979 (Box 43)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1970s (Box 43)
  - J.M. Freeman Sketchbook 1980 (Box 43)
  - Sketch of Sandy Miller 1974 (Box 43)
  - Cartoons by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Irish Tavern, and Night Scene, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Millie and Len, at the Mineshaft, n.d (Box 43)
  - Sketch of Bob Donovan 1975 (Box 43)
  - Sketch of Elizabeth Lausch 1979 (Box 43)
  - Robyn, Blondie at N.Y.C., n.d. (Box 43)
  - Dr. Nan Dyer 1979 (Box 43)
  - Rhonda, and Lovely Judy 1979 (Box 43)
  - Leslie, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Eva at Kinko's, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Chess Enthusiast, Chris Griffin, n.d. (Box 43)
  - T.J.'s UVA, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Ginny at Poe's 1945 (Box 43)
  - The Hartwell Woody Band 1979 (Box 43)
  - Lisa, Corrie, and Sally 1979 (Box 43)
  - Diane Reeder of New Jersey, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Ballard Cabell 1969 (Box 43)
  - Cute Teenagers from Waynesboro, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Laurie from Hawaii 1979 (Box 43)
  - Lovely Lucy, at the Graffiti 1980 (Box 43)
  - Celestia Chappell, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Evelyn, Rainbow Bartender, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Terese de Donne 1980 (Box 43)
  - Sissi at the Rainbow 1980 (Box 43)
  - Dr. Nan Dyer, n.d. (Box 43)
  - James Baskerville Berrier, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Cute Pat 1975 (Box 43)
  - Martha Tharp 1979 (Box 43)
  - Very Sexy Terry 1979 (Box 43)
  - Leslie at Poe's 1979 (Box 43)
  - Martha of Sweet Briar 1975 (Box 43)
  - Anne Jones, in front of the Rotunda 1974 (Box 43)
  - Another Girl Friend of UVA Medical Students 1970 (Box 43)
  - James Scales, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Courtney at University Diner 1980 (Box 43)
  - Sketch of Thomas Jefferson, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Gardy, Ralph, Meindert, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Judith at the Virginian 1979 (Box 43)
  - Elsie at Mineshaft 1979 (Box 43)
  - Beautiful Bonnie 1979 (Box 43)
  - Jungle Cat, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jean Myking, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Pat at the Virginian 1970 (Box 43)
  - A Waitress at Poe's 1970 (Box 43)
  - Lovely Courtney Johnston 1979 (Box 43)
  - Veteran 1974 (Box 43)
  - Nude, n.d. (Box 43)
  - The Sea Ship 1952 (Box 43)
  - Lori O'Conner 1979 (Box 43)
  - Annie Shire or Liz Davis 1976 (Box 43)
  - Anne Mabey, from Richmond 1979 (Box 43)
  - Dolf Beelen, from Holland, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Eva, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Heike, from Germany, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Sylvia Richter, from Germany 1979 (Box 43)
  - Beautiful Bonnie 1979 (Box 43)
  - Evergreens, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Clair 1952 (Box 43)
  - Joan, from UVA 1951 (Box 43)
  - Photo of an Unknown Woman, n.d. (Box 43)
  - (Box 43)
  - Red Necks and Hippies, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Minetta Tavern, NYC 1970 (Box 43)
  - Irvine Allen and Camille Simpson 1979 (Box 43)
  - Jim at the Virginian 1979 (Box 43)
  - Very Special Sarah, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jane, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Gayle, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jennifer Moody, art history student at UVA, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Uncle Bruce Visits Puerto Rico, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Patricia Frye 1979 (Box 43)
  - Melvin Frye 1979 (Box 43)
  - Donny Bruce, and Jimmy Fortune 1979 (Box 43)
  - Poe's 1979 (Box 43)
  - Lovely, but Silent, Pam 1980 (Box 43)
  - People at the National Boat Show 1970 (Box 43)
  - Mac 1974 (Box 43)
  - At the Bar Room 1975 (Box 43)
  - Open Air Car No. 4, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Once Upon a Mattress, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Larry Jackson, from NY, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Sandy Herring, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Don't Make Me Black, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jill, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Sandy 1970 (Box 43)
  - My Favorite 17 year-old 1975 (Box 43)
  - Stephen Bryant, of Dillwyn Va, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Ben and Julie and Sid and Ann, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Lynn and Michael, n.d. (Box 43)
  - John McLaughlin, Teacher, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Bridget Cobb 1975 (Box 43)
  - Kathleen, Jail Bate at Virginia, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jackie Laux at Fenwicks 1980 (Box 43)
  - Brine Shrimp 1969 (Box 43)
  - It's No Fun Being in the Sack Alone, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Sarah at Tony's, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Karin Hanon, from Michigan, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Theodore Turner, UVA 1970 (Box 43)
  - Jamie Beverly 1979 (Box 43)
  - Unidentified Painting, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Subway Scene 1954 (Box 43)
  - Meditation, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Nude Study 1952 (Box 43)
  - John Healy, n.d. (Box 43)
  - A Bunch of Bums, n.d. (Box 43)
  - John Kiever, n.d. (Box 43)
  - C-ville, Astromer 1980 (Box 43)
  - Judge Huff 1980 (Box 43)
  - Linda R. Thayer, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jill, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Ceci at the University Diner 1979 (Box 43)
  - Chuck Wagon, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Jim Proctor, Zeta Psi, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Valerie Schafer 1979 (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Verses by Freeman (Box 43)
  - Miscellaneous Items (Box 43)
  - Letters to Freeman 1961-1980 (Box 43)
  - Letter from Florence Cannariato to Freeman 1978-1981 (Box 43)
  - Newspaper articles about Pornography charge (Box 43)
  - Mr. Fred Wood correspondence with Freeman 1980 (Box 43)
  - Letter from Martha Macmillan to Freeman 1975 (Box 43)
  - Note from Ballard Cabell, n.d. (Box 43)
  - Lucy Freeman to Freeman 1976-1979 (Box 43)
  - Veteran Records 1978 (Box 43)
- Series X--Artifacts, n.d.
  - 2 Nightcaps (Box 44)
  - 1 infant dress (MWF) (Box 44)
  - 1 pr. child's shoes (BHC) (Box 44)
  - 1 set dentures (BHC?) (Box 44)
- Series XI--Publications and Miscellaneous Printed Matter
  - Miscellaneous Postcards (Box 45)
  - Making of the Jest galleys (Box 46)
  - Between Friends manuscript (Box 47)
  - Catalog of Cabell's Works 1977 (Box 48)
  - Abramson, Ben Style 1970 (Box 48)
  - The American Pen, newsletter and quarterly (Box 48)
  - Aprilis Gesta by JBC 1915 (Box 48)
  - The Arthur Machen Journal, vol. 1, no. 1 Summer 1963, with article about JBC 1963 (Box 48)
  - Bulletin of the Virginia State Library 1921 (Box 48)
  - Cabell in Love by Edgar MacDonald (Box 48)
  - Cabell Obituary, Richmond News-Leader May 6, 1958 (Box 48)
  - Church Programs (Box 48)
  - The Glasgow-Cabell Entente by Edgar MacDonald (Box 48)
  - Heredity: The Cause of racial Differences in Intelligence (Box 48)
  - James Branch Cabell: The Man and His Masks by Louis Untermeyer (Box 48)
  - Journal of JBC's illness 1957 (Box 48)
  - Limited Editions Club, Monthly Newsletter on JBC 1976 (Box 48)
  - Lord Fairfax's Friends Certificate (Box 48)
  - The Nation, Books I have Never Read, by JBC and others 1933 (Box 48)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 48)
  - Phone Numbers, addresses (Box 48)
  - Preservation News (Box 48)
  - Richmond Public Library Card of MFC 1973 (Box 48)
  - The Saturday Review of Literature 1933 (Box 48)
  - Shenandoah with essay by JBC Of Reverting to Old Friendships (Box 48)
  - Society for the Study of Southern Literature-newsletter (Box 48)
  - Virginia Cavalcade, Summer 1954 (Box 48)
  - The Villager, NYC 1934 (Box 48)
  - Why Collect Books by Lawrence W. Fox (Box 48)
  - Yorktown Country Club Life Membership 1924 (Box 48)
  - Wedding Document, JBC and Priscilla Bradley 1913 (Box 49)
  - Margaret W. Freeman, Red Cross First Aid Certificate 1912 (Box 49)
  - Genealogical Notes, MFC (Box 49)
  - Cabell, Ballard H.-Obituary (Box 50)
  - Diary Entries 1941-1945 (Box 50)
  - Fifty Letters 1920-1935 (Box 50)
  - Hamlet Had An Uncle-Second Annual Book Luncheon 1940 (Box 50)
  - Lore magazine 1966-1967 (Box 50)
  - Marhta S. Hobson: Estate Papers; John C. Freeman, executor (Box 50)
    Includes maps of Hobson Land, Buckingham County, Va 1916-1918
  - ODD Magazine, n.d. 1967 (Box 50)
  - Plantation Gardens catalog (Box 50)
  - Poe Messenge r, with photos of G. Stein in Richmond 1972 (Box 50)
  - Virginia Calender, Week by Week 1947 (Box 50)
  - Article on David Freed, local Richmond artist who did etching of Cabell 1974 (Box 53)
  - Book dealer catalogs and miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Colonial Dames publications 1970-1974 (Box 53)
  - The Golden Book Magazine-contains Cabell's The Jewell Merchants 1930 (Box 53)
  - Harper's Magazine-contains Cabell's The Satraps 1909 (Box 53)
  - The Literary Review, M.Y. Evening Post, contains Cabell's The Taboo in Literature Dec. 11, 1920 (Box 53)
  - Misc. article on JBC, Ellen Glasgow, Emily Clark, n.d. 1960s-1970s (Box 53)
  - Misc. Cabell relate publications, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Newspaper clipping on Willis A. Shell Jr. and Attic Press, Richmond Times Dispatch 1975 (Box 53)
  - Newspaper clipping, Editorial on Letters of James Branch Cabell, The Progress Index Petersburg, Va. 1975 (Box 53)
  - Proof sheets of Prefact to Devil's Own Dear Son from Nelson Bond Collection of JBC (Box 53)
  - Typed manuscript concerning geriatrics, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Shakespeare on the Village Press, prophesized in Sonnet 65 (Box 53)
  - Types and Type Design, by Goudy (Box 53)
  - Invitation to join Pilgrimage to Deepdene, n.d. (Box 53)
  - Keepsake Pilgrimage to Deepdene 1938 (Box 53)
  - The Bible an address by Frederic W. Goudy on the ocassion of the presentation of the Oxford Lectern Bible to the N.Y. School of Printing 1938 (Box 53)
  - Day Letter a Telegram from Ellen Glasgow 1938 (Box 53)
  - A Tribute to Bertha M. Goudy 1936 (Box 53)
  - Joe Bowles, Refusal Order Blank, n.d. (Box 53)
  - The Village Press 1903 (Box 53)
  - Recollections of C. Lauron Hopper 1938 (Box 53)
  - In Reply: An Open Letter to Frederic W. Goudy from Bruce Rogers 1938 (Box 53)
  - The Story of Saint Gonsol, Sain Francis and the Devil, by Frederic W. Goudy 1938 (Box 53)
  - First Goudy Cartoon, but Frank Holme 1900? (Box 53)